<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conlon Novak</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Conlon Novak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© {year} Conlon Novak.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 13:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Document Design Process Books</title><link>/portfolio/doc_design/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Dec 2020 13:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/doc_design/</guid><description>Impact: Reflecting on my Visual Design Process Key Concepts: Heirarchy, Progressive Disclosure, Grid Layouts, Visual/Verbal Balance, Intentional White Space
Tools: Adobe InDesign, Adobe Photoshop, Figma, Sketching, Design Critiques
Roles: Designer, Editor, Publisher, Printer
Duration: 1 semester
I am not a visual designer, which made the Document Design course I took in my last semester of graduate school all the more interesting; it was a course about physical media, taught and critiqued remotely (due to COVID) with digital tools and online submissions.</description></item><item><title>ThanOS</title><link>/portfolio/thanos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/thanos/</guid><description>Impact: Humor through Design Key Concepts: Scripting, Poor data management practices, Not taking ourselves too seriously
Tools: Linux Command Line, VIM, Sublime Text, Figma, Adobe Premiere, Zoom
Roles: Bash Script Developer, Storyboarder, Video Editor
Duration: 48 hours during PennApps XXI
Team Members: Emmanuel Eppinger, Connie Chao, and Deepayan Patra
This one is rather silly, but intentionally so. For PennApps XXI, we built a disk manager for Linux that places your information (and system files) entirely in the hands of destiny—in this case, the psuedorandom RANDOM function of Linux.</description></item><item><title>Voice-Enabled Services</title><link>/portfolio/vespa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 03:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/vespa/</guid><description>Impact: Designing for Underserved Groups Key Concepts: Empathy, Coordinated Entry, Meeting people where they are, Conversational User Interfaces, Government Technology, Agile Development
Tools: Voiceflow, Amazon Alexa, Facebook Messenger API, Figma, Adobe InDesign, Adobe Premiere, Zoom
Roles: Scrum Master, Client Manager, Design Researcher, User Experience Designer, Web Developer, Video Editor
Duration: 7 months
Team Members: Laura Beth Fulton, Tommy Byler, Simran Jobanputra, and Judy Chun
Getting public assistance can be prohibitively hard, especially for people affected by disability and discrimination.</description></item><item><title>Demand Change at CMU</title><link>/portfolio/demand-cmu-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/demand-cmu-support/</guid><description>Impact: Developing to Support Community Activism Key Concepts: Community Organizing, Information Transparency, Oversight, Accountability
Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript
Roles: Archivist, Web Developer, Community Activist
Duration: Ongoing since June 2020
This project was born out of a particularly frustrating time to be a student at Carnegie Mellon University, made more difficult by the seemingly endless supply of outrage, energy, and effort that wasn&amp;rsquo;t being put towards a single, combined effort to effect change.</description></item><item><title>Senior Honors Thesis</title><link>/portfolio/thesis/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 09:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/thesis/</guid><description>Impact: Researching Across Cultures Title: “Se Graban Memorias,” A Contextual Analysis of El Paquete Semanal, Human Networks, and Internet Access in Camagüey, Cuba
Key Concepts: Ethnographic Research, Internet Connectivity, Sneakernets, Emergent Cultural Phenomena, Cuban History
Tools: Field Research, Interviews, Correspondence, Literature Reviews, Background Research
Roles: Author, Interviewer, Videographer, Video Editor
Duration: 18 months (Two week-long trips to Cuba in Mar. 2019 and Jan. 2020, respectively)
Faculty Advisor: Dr. Therese Tardio, Modern Languages</description></item><item><title>Football Explained</title><link>/portfolio/footballexplained/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 08:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/footballexplained/</guid><description>Impact: Calling an Inclusivity Audible Key Concepts: Data Analysis, Productive Group Facilitation, Public Speaking
Tools: Microsoft Excel, Adobe Photoshop, Google Slides
Roles: Designer, Facilitator, Presenter
Duration: 2.5 hours
Team Members: Amanda Bao, Sun Min Kim, Lizette Hurtado Garzon, Xinkai Chen, and Umut Soysal
My dad swore that the best way to experience a baseball game was to listen to it on our local radio station. He believed this so fervently that he would bring an FM radio with earbuds to the baseball stadium with us to listen to the caster describe what we were seeing in the ballpark, explaining the rules of the game to me along the way.</description></item><item><title>Babble</title><link>/portfolio/babble/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/babble/</guid><description>Impact: Prototyping for Emergency Situations Key Concepts: Near-Field Communications, Android Beam, Point-to-Point Wi-Fi, Offline Communications, Emergency Response
Tools: Java, MongoDB, Android Studio, iMovie
Roles: Database Architect, App Developer, Video Editor
Duration: 48 hours during PennApps XVIII
Awards: Top 30 Hack, Lutron IoT Prize, Best Use of MongoDB Stitch, Best Hack for Resilience - Wharton Risk Center
Team Members: Aneek Mukherjee and Emmanuel Eppinger
Inspired by the vulnerability of traditional communication infrastructure to widespread natural disaster, Babble is a chat platform that is able to be installed, setup, and used 100% offline.</description></item><item><title>Labyrinthine</title><link>/portfolio/labyrinthine/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2016 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/labyrinthine/</guid><description>Impact: Developing a Flexible Game Engine Key Concepts: Game Design, Raycasting, 2.5D Rendering, Procedural Generation, Optimization
Tools: Python, PyGame
Roles: Developer, QA Tester, Player
Duration: 7 weeks, term project for Fundamentals of Programming and Computer Science (15-112)
Labyrinthine is a game built on a simple, custom ray-casting game engine that takes a 2D list of coordinates (for wall placement) and flat image textures (of the walls and the skybox) and turns them into 3D-ish environments by “propping up” these flat objects at different distances from the player.</description></item><item><title>Teach Tiles</title><link>/portfolio/teach-tiles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/teach-tiles/</guid><description>Impact: Designing for Future Educational Technologies Key Concepts: Augmented Reality, Educational Technology
Tools: Unity, Vuforia Mixed Reality API
Roles: User Experience Designer, Graphic Designer, Videographer, Video Editor
Duration: 24 hours during HackCMU 2016
Team Members: Tom Wildenhain and Benjamin Johnson-Staub
TeachTiles is both a really interesting design concept and an excellent example of how low- and mid-fidelity prototypes can be developed quickly, while still yielding meaningful engagement and feedback from people.</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>Conlon Novak (he/him) is a developer, designer, analyst, and consultant, with a focus on impact of all kinds — from public policy and societal, to social and individual.
He attended Carnegie Mellon University from 2016 to 2020, earning a Master of Human-Computer Interaction degree and completing the program&amp;rsquo;s capstone consulting project
alongside his team.
During his undergraduate studies at CMU for his B.S. in Information Systems and Human-Computer Interaction (with a minor in Film and Media Studies), he completed a senior honors thesis,
as well as a number of hackathon projects.</description></item></channel></rss>