<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>hackathon on Conlon Novak</title><link>/tags/hackathon/</link><description>Recent content in hackathon on Conlon Novak</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© {year} Conlon Novak.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/hackathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ThanOS</title><link>/portfolio/thanos/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/thanos/</guid><description>Impact: Humor through Design Key Concepts: Scripting, Poor data management practices, Not taking ourselves too seriously
Tools: Linux Command Line, VIM, Sublime Text, Figma, Adobe Premiere, Zoom
Roles: Bash Script Developer, Storyboarder, Video Editor
Duration: 48 hours during PennApps XXI
Team Members: Emmanuel Eppinger, Connie Chao, and Deepayan Patra
This one is rather silly, but intentionally so. For PennApps XXI, we built a disk manager for Linux that places your information (and system files) entirely in the hands of destiny—in this case, the psuedorandom RANDOM function of Linux.</description></item><item><title>Babble</title><link>/portfolio/babble/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/babble/</guid><description>Impact: Prototyping for Emergency Situations Key Concepts: Near-Field Communications, Android Beam, Point-to-Point Wi-Fi, Offline Communications, Emergency Response
Tools: Java, MongoDB, Android Studio, iMovie
Roles: Database Architect, App Developer, Video Editor
Duration: 48 hours during PennApps XVIII
Awards: Top 30 Hack, Lutron IoT Prize, Best Use of MongoDB Stitch, Best Hack for Resilience - Wharton Risk Center
Team Members: Aneek Mukherjee and Emmanuel Eppinger
Inspired by the vulnerability of traditional communication infrastructure to widespread natural disaster, Babble is a chat platform that is able to be installed, setup, and used 100% offline.</description></item><item><title>Teach Tiles</title><link>/portfolio/teach-tiles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2016 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/teach-tiles/</guid><description>Impact: Designing for Future Educational Technologies Key Concepts: Augmented Reality, Educational Technology
Tools: Unity, Vuforia Mixed Reality API
Roles: User Experience Designer, Graphic Designer, Videographer, Video Editor
Duration: 24 hours during HackCMU 2016
Team Members: Tom Wildenhain and Benjamin Johnson-Staub
TeachTiles is both a really interesting design concept and an excellent example of how low- and mid-fidelity prototypes can be developed quickly, while still yielding meaningful engagement and feedback from people.</description></item></channel></rss>